When we said that the framework didn't want us
to run network operations on the main thread, what
is the main thread? Well, Android apps run by
default on the main thread, also called the UI thread.
It handles all the user input as well as
the output, such as screen drawing. Thus we want
to avoid any time-consuming operations here, otherwise the URI
is going to stutter. Instead, kick off a background worker
thread if you have to do some long-running
work. This includes doing network calls, decoding bitmaps, or
reading, and writing from the database. Okay. So, somehow,
we have to move the networking code off the
main thread. But how are we going to do
that? Well there are several options, but let's look
for the name of the Android class that simplifies
background thread creation and UI thread synchronization, so that
the results from the background work will come back onto the
main thread, and then we can use it to update our
UI. Search online and figure out the answer to this question
and then enter the class name in the box. Here's some
advice for you. If you ever get stuck on how to
do something in Android and you can't find it on the
developer's site you can try to check stackoverflow.com. It's a question
and answer site that many Android developers use as a valuable resource.
So chances are likely that someone has
already asked a similar question that you have.